Hello Hello
Everyone Welcome to my YouTube channel
Keypad Simple In today's video we
will discuss about the
second quarter results of ICICI Lombard General Insurance
Yesterday they declared their second
quarter results and
in this video we will discuss
how the results were and whether we should buy their shares in future and
this should also be avoided and
before moving ahead if you have not yet subscribed to the channel then
please
motivate us by subscribing So first of all
if we talk about the company overview
then ICICI Lombard is a
leading private sector general insurance
company of India and it provides all the non-life
insurances
like travel insurance auto insurance
health insurance home insurance etc.
So if we talk about the product mix of life
then their portfolio value
is diversified their main revenue comes from auto
insurance health travel personal
accidental fire insurance
so if we talk about the financials of the second quarter
then their profit after tax was
446 crores their numbers are not comparable with last year
because they have just acquired
Bharti AXA  It has merged with and
due to that they had to restate the numbers of the current year
but even if we compare then
their income has increased by 32.4%
their profit has increased by 7.4% to Rs.
440 crore and the main region in this is
better claims for Rakhine where
in health insurance area it was Rs. 180 crore
which was much less than the previous quarter
in the last quarter they had to present health insurance claims worth Rs. 600 crore
and due to which their profit had
fallen by 60.2% in the last quarter it was returning to Rs. 152 crore in the last quarter
apart from this their board commented Rs.
4 in the final tweet which was
recorded on 1st November
so if it will be discussed whether there is scope for
general insurance of non-life insurance sector in the coming time
then the answer is
that there is massive growth opportunity in India for
general insurance if we talk like this then
India is the fourth largest general insurance
market and globally 14th largest general insurance market
apart from this  If compared to the world average, the
insurance penetration in India is
1431. A
large population of India is under-insured.
Apart from this, if we talk about premium as a percentage of
GDP, then it is 49
percent in 2019, whereas in India it is only one percent.
And if we talk about premium per capita, then
in West Bengal,
$5,754 is offered for insurance in 2019,
whereas in India it is only nineteen dollars. So
overall you can say that there is a lot of scope for insurance in India.
Even now,
if we talk about the share price of China, then they have
given a model tractor of nineteen percent in one year. Although in three years
they gave a good return of 86 percent,
but if we talk about 2021, it has
not done at all. The share has given a
negative return of 1.3 percent. Apart from this,
in the last one month also it has been around eight percent
and the main reason for this is that they
provide health insurance, in
which the calibration has increased a lot due to the corona.
Due to which they had to
bear a lot of losses and if we make a product and
see the ticket sure, then they
tell the average price as 1672 and there the higher side is
9037 and the lower side is 1116, so from today
's closing, their target
price is 11% higher
and if we look at its fundamentals, then it is a
large cap company, Pir Ashwin's is a little
high and the reason for this is that you had a
little impact due to Kuber, if the
profits improve in the coming time,
then you will see that its
valuation will become tractor, return on
equity is set at 18, which is okay and it is a
debt free company, so if we talk about my
personal opinion whether its shares should be bought, then
if I tell you the good things about the
company first, then it has also
merged with Bharti AXA, so this energy pack will be
visible in the coming quarter, apart from this,
in my previous page I saw that India is very
much under-invested, there is a lot of mass
growth opportunity in insurance and
people want insurance.  Awareness is huge. With the
arrival of Corbett, they have relied
that paying insurance premium
is very important because it may be needed at any time. Apart from this, the
main thing that was packing their profits was Thuku
VAT health claims. Firstly, the company is doing better,
they have kept better reinsurance and
provisions. Apart from this, as things are
improving, it is expected that the
coming quarters will be good for the company.
If we talk about what is the matter for the company, then
if there is any third thing like
VAT, then it can be a matter of concern,
it can impact their recovery
or some other unplanned surprise comes.
Apart from this, if the competition in this area
increases even a little, then it can be a little challenging for them. So,
if that is
considered my personal opinion, then I think
that this stock is worth having in the portfolio
because a good correction has already taken place and the
words have been passed for the company. And further,
like the insurance score, then I
think that from here you can gain 10 to 30 percent.  It
can be seen in medium to long
term, so in my personal opinion,
this stock can be taken in the portfolio
even at the current price and even if there is a correction
and as always I will give a disclaimer
that if you want to invest in it
then talk to your friend or advisor, do
your research and after that if you are
comfortable then only invest in it
and if you liked this video
then please like, subscribe
to the channel and follow us on Twitter.
Thank you so much for watching and God
bless you all.